谁听说过北极有酷暑期
Whoever heard of a heatwave in the Arctic?
欢迎来到新常态
Welcome to the new normal.
我们站在北极巨型的冰冠上 这里的温度只有32华氏度（0摄氏度）
We're standing on a gigantic ice cap, and it's 32 Fahrenheit.
欢迎来到北极的夏天
Welcome to the Arctic summer.
华氏度
Fahrenheit?
等等 你刚刚用的是过时的英制单位吗？
Wait, did you just use that antiquated Imperial measurement?
是的 我是那么用的 瑞典人
Yeah, I did, Sweden.
混蛋 我是挪威人 不是瑞典人
I'm from Norway, A-hole. Not Sweden!
有什么区别吗？
Is there any difference?
你们美国人完全跟不上世界的步伐
You Americans! You're so out of step with the rest of the world.
你是个科学家 看在上帝的份上
You're a scientist, for God's sake.
冰河学家
Glaciologist.
你们两个基友聊天就像一对小姑娘
You two knob jockeys sound like a couple of Sheilas.
咱们还是弄点岩石样本回村子吧
Let's get these core samples and get back to the outpost.
伙计们 我们打到什么东西了
Guys, we hit something.
这些冰有年月了
This is some mean ice.
所以人们才叫它陈年冰
That's why they call it the Old Cold!
是的 我估计需要提高了挖掘机转速
Yeah, well, I reckon just increase the bit speed.
咱们加把劲钻穿它
Let's blast right through it.
嘿 伙计们
Hey, guys?
我探测到冰下有地震脉冲
I'm getting a seismic spike in the ice.
是的 可能只是一次地壳均衡复原
Yeah, well, it's probably just an isostatic rebound.
真见鬼
Like hell, it is.
我的屏幕上显示强烈的地磁异常
I'm getting a big-ass magnetic anomaly on my screen.
不管是什么 它是个活物 而且个头很大
Whatever it is, it's alive, and it's big.
坚冰之下没有大型生命体
There are no big life forms that live in solid ice.
可能是反向散射触动了岩层
Maybe the backscatter effect brought up a rock formation.
是的 也许是只复活节兔子
Yeah, and maybe it's the Easter Bunny!
这不是岩石 而且肯定不是复活节兔子
This is not a rock, and it sure as shit isn't the Easter Bunny.
笨蛋
Dumbass!
检查一下
Check it out.
澳洲人
Aussie!
澳洲人 澳洲人 澳洲人 听到没有
Aussie? Aussie? Aussie, do you copy?
什么鬼东西
What the hell?
- 什么... - 拉出来 拉出来
- What... - Get it out! Get it out!
快点 拉出来 加油 快点快点 美国佬
Come on, get it out. Come on! Come on! Come on! Come on, Yank!
不..不..
No! No!
美国佬
Yankee!
Yank!
不
No.
No!
不
《异形魔怪：极寒之日》
是真的吗 甘莫 一台运动检测器
Really, Gummer? A motion detector?
完美
Perfection.
还有活人啊,外面都热成鬼了
Man alive, it's hot as balls out there!
把手放在我能看到的地方,伙计
Hands where I can see them, partner.
哎哟 甘莫 你知道我是谁
Oh, gee-whiz, Gummer! You know who I am!
是我 特派员 迪克维德
It's me, Special Agent Dalkwed.
来吧特派员 迪克维德
Do it, Agent Dickweed.
你是在恐吓联邦公职人员吗？
Are you threatening a federal officer?
那要看情况人 收税员
That all depends, Taxman.
棍子和石子 那是支气枪吗 甘莫
Sticks and stones. Is that a pellet gun, Gummer?
你打赌它就是吗
You bet your sweet ass it is!
噢 你什么时候开始玩玩具了
Oh, since when do you play with toys?
不关你的事 你带枪了
Since none of your damn business. You armed?
当然带枪了
Of course, I'm armed.
所有美国财政部的特派员都有枪
All Special Agents with the United States Treasury are armed.
你是知道的
You know that.
特派员 你很会算计啊
Special Agent! You're a bean counter.
你这是持械私闯民宅
This here is private property in an open-carry state.
你不是碰巧对所谓的财产
And you wouldn't happen to have any financial interest
感兴趣吧 是吗
in said property, now would you?
没有 到别处收租子去吧
Nope! Go slap a lien somewhere else.
已经收过了
Already have.
嘿
Hey.
我看你支持其他球对了
I see you've changed teams.
嗯？
Hmm?
不 只是帽子换了
No, just hats!
Cubbies赢了那个赛季是个奇迹
Well, it was a miracle the Cubbies won that series.
坦白说 甘莫 那正是你需要的
And frankly, Gummer, that's what you're gonna need,
奇迹
a miracle.
因为现在 我抓住你的小辫子了
'Cause right now, your ass is in my hands.
说重点 迪克维德
Your point, Dickweed?
国税局认为你的报税情况不实
Your tax position has been deemed frivolous by the IRS
而且你的财产也据此被查封了
and your property has hereby been seized.
什么 你不能这样
What? You can't!
我可以 而且我已经做了
I can, and I did!
你的财产是国税局的了 甘莫
The IRS owns you, Gummer,
到时候我们可以没收你所有的物品
until such time as we can arrange for confiscation of any and all items
都要被拿去充公
deemed suitable for government auction.
你个狗娘养的
You parasitic son of a bitch!
是啊 你的...
Yeah, your...
你那套完美的武器 也可以抬高价格
Your well-endowed battery of firearms might raise enough to make a dent
用以消减你的罚款和利息
in your failure to file penalties and interest.
我发现你这是在幸灾乐祸 迪克维德先生
I detect the odorous stench of Schadenfreude, Agent Dickweed!
咱们法庭上见
I will see you in court!
法庭上？噢 噢 不
In court? Oh. Oh, no!
用不着了 甘莫
We're way past that, Gummer.
用不着了
Way past.
滚出去
Out of here!
再见了 甘莫
Goodbye, Gummer.
轻点推门 当心夹到你的屁股
And don't let the door dislodge that poker up your ass!
噢 我会小心的
Oh, I'll be really careful.
- 又一个顾客满意而归了 - 什么
- Another satisfied customer? - What?
想我没
Did you miss me?
是啊 就像我屁股上的疖子一样
Yeah, like a boil on my ass.
我看你拿到了供应申请
I see you got the supply req.
噢是的 第八条太有吸引力了
Oh, yeah. That eighth text was a charm.
嘿 欢迎回来 阳光小子
"Hey, welcome home, sonny boy!"
“噢 见到你真高兴”“离开多久了”
"Oh, good to see you." "How long's it been?"
“四五个星期”“好吧 视频拍摄得怎样”
"Four or five weeks?" "Okay. How'd the video shoot go?"
法西斯走狗
Fascist jackals!
噢 政府的人 准没好事
Ooh, Government plates. That can't be good.
让我猜猜 国税局
Let me guess. IRS?
他们没有权利在这里为所欲为 侵占他人财产
They've got no right to waltz in here and seize a man's property.
得了 伯特 你把联邦政府拒之门外的时间可比韦斯利.斯奈普斯还长
Come on, Burt. You've been flipping off the Feds longer than Wesley Snipes.
也是破记录了
That's got to be a record.
正是这事引起了波士顿倾茶事件
This is the very thing that sparked the Boston Tea Party.
无代表不纳税
No taxation without representation!
约迪决定留在里诺的律师所是件好事 不是吗
It's a good thing Jodi decided to stay at that law firm in Reno, huh?
- 就在这里等死吗 - 没人想等死
- Lets you squat here? - Nobody's squatting.
我现在经营这家商店
I'm managing the store now.
真的 恭喜
Really? Congratulations.
我真的很欣赏你在这里所做的一切
And I really love what you've done with the place.
知道什么叫贪婪吗 啧啧
You really put the hyphen back in anal-retentive. Jeez.
用不着你挖苦我
I can do without the sarcasm, son.
噢 得了 伯特 别介意
Oh, come on, Burt. Don't be hurt.
好了 现在我回来了 咱们从新来过 好吗？
All right, now that I'm back, let's hit that reset button, huh?
在视频网站上加点新鲜事
Put some fresh content up on YouTube,
试着重振“靶心”频道
try and resurrect that Bull's-Eye Brand.
不用视镜了 我的导演放弃我了
Not doing prepper videos anymore. My director quit on me.
不 他没有 他就在这
No, he didn't. He's right here.
我刚刚有点发神经
I just had a small mental health break.
那顶帽子怎么了 等一下
What's up with that hat? Wait a minute.
支持的球队换了？
You change teams?
没有 只是顶帽子
No, just hats!
放松点 伯特 看 我知道你讨厌执导
Take it easy, Burt. Look, I know you hate taking direction,
而我的风格对你来说太即兴 好吧
and my style's way too improvisational for you, okay?
天呐 你真让我头痛
Lord, you're giving me a headache.
得了 伯特 对我的看法中肯点
Come on, Burt, meet me in the middle.
记得把五块钱放到钱箱里
Make sure you put $5 in that cash box.
什么钱
For what?
那瓶啤酒不是免费的
That beer doesn't come free.
要打烊了
You're closing up?
老兄 我没到时间呢
Dude, it's not Miller time yet.
你找不到安身的地方
You can't find your beach.
打盹时间到
Time for some shut-eye.
你什么时候开始中午还要打盹了？
Since when do you "shut-eye" in the middle of the afternoon?
从你出现开始
Since you showed up!
你想知道我为什么去脱衣舞夜总会
You wonder why I go to strip clubs!
这里究竟发生了什么
What the hell happened here?
有东西从冰下袭击了他们
Something attacked them from under the ice.
不可能
It can't be!
请讲
Chang's.
哦 伯特 出什么事了
Yo, Burt! What's up?
健身 一起来吧
Calisthenics. Feel free to join in.
我想我还是算了吧
I think I'll pass.
你想挣钱吗？去整理货架吧
You wanna earn your keep, go stock some shelves.
乐意效劳 但是有你的电话
I'd love to, but you've got a phone call.
留言吧
Take a message.
我说了
I tried,
但是有位女士正在线等
but there's a lady holding on the line,
顺便说一下 她的声音很性感
who's got a very sexy phone voice, by the way.
她让我转告你 他们已经有了 呃...
She told me to tell you that they've got, uh...
我认不出来我写的了
I can't read my writing.
那个词是...怎么说的..她有了..呃
What does that word... What does that say? That she's got, uh...
- 格拉波虫？在哪里 - 甘莫先生
- Graboids? Where? - Mr. Gummer?
是的 你是？
Affirmative. Who's this?
丽塔.西姆斯博士 我在加拿大的努勒维特致电给你
Dr. Rita Sims. I'm calling from Nunavut Province, Canada.
我们在北纬67度
We're 67 degrees north.
- 那是加拿大极地地区 - 是的
- That's the Canadian Arctic. - Yes, it is.
我是一个国际研究小组的站点负责人
I'm the station leader of an international research team.
我们在哈利峡谷
We' re based at Bo顃e Canyon.
你是怎么知道这个号码的？从政府的人手里吗？
How'd you get this number? You from the government?
她性感吗？
Is she hot?
我有个同事对你的工作很熟悉
Well, I have an associate familiar with your work.
我觉得她的性取向一定有点问题
I think your associate must be half a bubble off plumb.
那也是我的第一反应 但实际上她非常聪明
That was my first reaction, but she's actually very bright.
她知道很多关于格拉波虫的传说
She knows a lot about Graboid mythology.
格拉波虫不是传说 但他们只存在于沙漠里
Graboids are no myth, but they're a desert phenomenon.
我觉得这东西一两句话说不清 怎么称呼你
I think this is a colossal time suck, Miss, uh...
西姆斯博士
Dr. Sims.
格拉波虫无法存在于北极地区 西姆斯博士
Graboids do not and cannot exist in the Arctic, Dr. Sims!
- 不可能 - 性感的话约约她
- Impossible. - Ask her if she's hot.
不大可能 但也不是不可能
Improbable but not impossible.
- 你是谁 - 我是瓦莱利
- Who's this? - This is Valerie.
首先 我要说 作为一名专业的格拉波虫爱好者
First, let me say that, as a major Graboid enthusiast,
多年来我一直很钦佩您的工作 我就知道这些
I have admired your work for years. Here's what I know.
格拉波虫是潜伏在地下的蠕虫状捕食者
Graboids are subterranean worm-like predator
跟地球上现存和远古的生命形态的基因不同
unlike any other life form cataloged in Earth's genetic or fossil record.
当格拉波虫长到成虫时 它可以
When fully grown, a Graboid can reach up
达到10米长 20吨重
to 10 meters in length and weigh up to 20 tons.
它们半钢性类似骨骼的内部结构被子一层皮质的甲壳包裹着
Their semi-rigid internal structure is covered by a leathery carapace.
它们是昼行性动物 但没有眼睛
They're daytime hunters and have no eyes,
但最吸引我的是它们捕食的敏锐性
but what's most fascinating to me about their predatory acuity
拿的是心灵感应
is that it's based on vibration.
继续 我听着呢
Go on. I'm listening.
它们有巨大的黑色装甲喙嘴 两个钩状的上颚
They have a massive black armored beak and two hooked mandibles,
分布在颌的两边
one on either side of their jaw.
这个物种是前寒武纪生物 有长而有力的蛇形触手
The species is Precambrian and have long and powerful snake-like tentacles,
可以诱捕三米以内的猎物
which can reach three meters to ensnare their prey.
如果你喜欢 我可以给你411
If you'd like, I can give you the 411
在形态学变异中
On the morphological subspecies
也被称为爆尾鸟 墨西哥航空公司燃烧器
known as the Ass Blaster a.k.a. Mexicana Combustus.
你是格拉波虫科学的探索者 小组 但是我...
You're a treasure-trove of Graboidology, Miss, but I...
你在两个不同的大洲捕杀过它们 甘莫先生
You've hunted and killed them on two different continents, Mr. Gummer.
所以我坚持要致电给你
That's why I insisted that we call.
但你为何确信这次袭击是格拉波虫？
But why are you so sure this is a Graboid attack?
伤亡现场特征明显
The kill site has all the telltale signs.
除了地理位置
Except for location.
我不知道 应该叫直觉 第六感
I don't know. Call it a gut feeling, intuition.
我们需要你的帮助 甘莫先生 越快越好
We need your help, Mr. Gummer, and we need it ASAP!
想想这次冒险 格拉波虫在北极地区
Think of the adventure, Graboids in the Arctic.
这次完全不同以往
This could be a whole new ballgame.
球员上场
Batter up!
太好了
Yes.
你还没问她性不性感呢
You never asked if she was hot!
- 你去哪？ - 第二局 我来了
- Where are you going? - Round two! I'm coming with.
拒绝请求
Request denied.
什么？得了吧 收起你霸道哥的嘴脸
What? Come on, here, stop being Burt for a minute,
别把我排出在外了
and logic this thing out with me.
这是收看伯特.甘莫的靶心频道的好机会
This is our chance to revive Burt Gummer's Bull's-Eye Brand,
把你从收税员手里解救出来 老兄
get you free of the taxman, dude!
说真的 你的账本上有了很多赤字
Let's be honest. You've got a lot of red in your ledger.
我的财务状况跟你没毛关系
My financial status is none of your damn beeswax.
而且你只会碍事
And you'll just be in the way.
噢 就像我在南非那次
Oh, like I was in South Africa? Huh?
就那一次 以后再也不会了
That was a one-off! Nothing more.
你看问题的角度不对啊 朋友
You're looking at this through the wrong end of the telescope here, friend.
你的遗产咋办？
What about your legacy, huh?
什么东西
What about it?
你还知道其它的格拉波虫猎人吗？
Do you know of any other Graboid hunters out there?
我不知道
Uh, I don't.
我知道 知道吗？大脚猎人...不
I know, you know, Bigfoot hunters... No!
你是伯特.甘莫 你只有一条命
You're Burt Gummer. You're a one-off!
来吧 伙计 教我 投资未来
Come on, man, teach me! Pay it forward.
噢 我还没死呢
Oh, I'm not dead yet.
我知道 我也没兴趣谈论你的死亡率
I know, and I'm not interested in talking about your mortality, either,
但是想想吧 谁来接你的班
but think about it. Who's gonna fill your shoes
当你跑不过或干不过这些怪兽时
when you can no longer outrun or outgun these beasts, huh?
我得跟你说道说道
I've got to tell you something.
伯特.甘莫搞了双高跟鞋
Burt Gummer's got some big-ass shoes to fill.
12码
Size 12s.
我在你的衣帽间看到了
I've seen you in the locker room.
你是我的法定继承人 是吗？
And you're my heir apparent. Is that it?
你已经带我完胜格拉波虫挑战
You already led me through one Graboid gauntlet.
- 你还有很多不知道的东西 - 我有同感
- There's a lot you still don't know. - Exactly my point.
学习会很有趣 我就是罗塞塔石碑 狗
Learning can be fun! Rosetta Stone me, dawg.
那是一本像样的搏击读本
It was a decent enough combat primer.
见鬼 是的 我是你的幕僚
Hell, yeah, it was! I was your wingman.
幕僚？我看更像是翼形螺帽
Wingman? More like wingnut!
算了 那有点...
Come on, that's...
我觉得那有点刻薄了
That's a little harsh, I think.
该死
Damn it!
你愿意服从命令吗？
Are you willing to follow orders?
我是说 有时候 我不...
I mean, sometimes, I don't...
听着 在战场上最重要的六英寸
Look, the most important six inches on the battlefield
在你的两眼之间 明白吗？
are between your ears. You got that?
我觉得我的脸不止6英尺宽 应该是6.5
I'd like to think I have more. I think I'm 6.5.
别跟我耍嘴皮子
Don't crack wise with me.
明白 遵命 长官
Sir, yes, sir!
还有 那张加拿大皇家骑警5590号
And have you filled out
非居民携枪豁免权的申请表 你填完了没？
the requisite non-resident special exemption RCMP-5590 form?
长官...
Sir...
- 你说啥？ - 那张加拿大皇家骑警5590号申请表
- What? - The RCMP-5590 form!
你要想带着枪进加拿大 就得填那表
For that firearm you're planning on bringing into Canada.
没
No.
那你最好下一份 快填
Well, then you better download one and fill it out pronto.
拿你的北极装备去
Grab your arctic gear.
YES
Man!
欢迎来到加拿大
Welcome to the Great White North, eh!
你是说不毛之地吧
Otherwise known as Nowheresville.
从这往南1000英里才是呢
You're about 1,000 miles north of there.
你现在是在..呃
You're somewhere between, uh,
既没多少人来过也没多少人想来的地方
Ain't-Never-Been and Don't-Wanna-Go.
冰川都去哪了
Where are all the glaciers?
化了 雪橇的失业率已经创历史新高了
Melting. Sled dog unemployment's at an all-time high.
我们还要多长时间才到
How much longer till we're there?
用不了多久了 前面拐外弯就到了
Not far. Just around the bend.
你的GPS导航呢？
Where's your GPS?
你现在是在北极圈内
You're in the Arctic Circle.
GPS定位也起不了多大作用
Satellites up here are more miss than hit.
不过别担心 路线图都在我脑子里
But don't worry. It's all up here.
那才是最靠谱的
That's reassuring.
后面什么情况 甘莫先生
How is it back there, Mr. Gummer?
我的地震监测仪完全派不上用场
My seismic vibration monitor is completely useless.
那当然 到科研站后 你就可以联网了
Yeah, well, you can log in to the inter-Web when we get you on station.
- 好 - 话说我可是你节目的忠实粉丝
- Peachy. - Hey, I'm a big fan of your series.
我特别喜欢把肉干和昆虫当做蛋白质来源的那集
I loved that episode on dried meats and insects as proteins.
你这是要把家酿酒偷运出去啊
I see you're smuggling home-brew grain alcohol into dry territory.
嗯 当地部落当局面非常正派
Well, the local tribal authority are a bit blue-nosed,
我只能悄悄的偷运点酒
so I'm forced to bring it in under the radar.
沉默是金 对吧
Don't ask, don't tell, right?
YES
Yeah.
特拉维斯
Travis!
我看到了
I see it.
- 不可能吧 - 真的是
- It can't be. - It is.
- 真的什么？ - 一次空袭将要发生
- It is what? - We got a hostile aerial incursion.
我们现在海拔多高
What's your altitude?
1400英尺
1,400 feet.
我建议你躲避 降落飞机
I suggest you take evasive action and put this plane on the ground.
北极竟有爆尾鸟
Ass Blasters in the Arctic?
它们在瞄准你的飞机引擎
They're keying in on your engine!
- 对 它们对热源很敏感 - 它们是谁
- Yeah, they're heat seekers. - Who's they?
爆尾鸟
Ass Blasters!
- 机鸟互撞 - 我们的引擎熄火了
- Bird strike. - We've lost the engine.
不是吧 天哪
No shit, Sherlock!
赶快迫降 快
Get this down! Now!
做好冲撞准备
Stand by for some chop!
我们要坠机了
Does that mean crash?
跟人类斗 万有引力从不失手
Gravity never loses!
我们顶多打个平手
The best we can hope for is a draw!
- 迎接大冲撞吧 - 什么冲撞
- Brace for impact! - Impact? What impact?
我们成功了
And we're here!
天哪 我们得赶紧出去
Whoa. We're so out of here!
哎哟 不好
Oh, no.
黑衣人来了
Here they come, the men in black.
哎呀呀 看看谁来了
Well, well, well! What do we have here?
是《猫和老鼠》里的汤姆和杰瑞
Tom and Jerry?
还有《冰上大歌舞》的弗里克跟弗兰克
Frick and Frank?
咦 不对 更像是《虎豹小霸王》里的布奇和圣丹斯小子
No, more like Butch and Sundance.
还有《警界双雄》里的斯塔斯基和哈金森
Starsky and Hutch.
我好像闻到酒味了
Do I smell alcohol?
我的飞机用的时候生物燃料
My bird runs on bio-fuel.
可你们却没少往我们第一民族的地盘上运私酒吧
And you're bootlegging moonshine into a First Nations territory?
这可是一大禁忌啊
That is a big time no-no!
那我们就不客气了 别介意
You don't mind if we help ourselves now, do you?
钱还是要给的吧
Well, there's a matter of payment, eh?
都算在我头了
Put it on my tab.
请问你大名
And who might you be?
你在这儿忙着追杀怪虫的这段时间里
I'm your next-door neighbor
我就是你对门邻居了
while you're up here on your little worm hunt.
但我们没心思招待客人 所以你们要小心点
But there's no welcome mat on my doorstep, so tread lightly.
给你个建议 甘莫先生
A piece of advice, Mr. Gummer.
要不妨碍我做事 老实交税
You stay out of my way and pay your taxes.
我丑话说在前头
Consider yourself properly warned.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
我哪知道 你说呢
I don't know. Do you?
既然我们是邻居 那我也给你点建议
Since we're neighbors, here's some neighborly advice.
在我解决掉这儿的怪虫问题之前 把你的人撤走
Beat a retreat until I get this area cleared out.
走？没门 我们才刚安顿下来
Retreat? Hell, no. We're just getting started up here.
那就另找个地儿
Then find a safe place to hunker down.
我丑话也说到前头
Consider yourself properly warned.
你认识这个家伙吗
You know that skid mark?
你都知道些什么关于他的事
What can you tell me about him?
据说他是来这儿
Well, rumor has it he's up here working
搞一些51区之类的事
on some Area 51 stuff.
美国高级什么局...
Some joint US-Canadian turd factory
建一个美加合资的破工厂
being developed by Harpo... Darpo...
美国国防部高级研究计划局
You mean DARPA?
正是 你知道他们？
That's the one! Know them?
当然 他们就是邪恶的代名词
Yeah, they're the acronym for evil.
你就是瓦莱利？
You must be Valerie?
正是 乐意为您效劳 谢谢您回应了我们的求救
At your service. And thanks for answering our SOS.
嗯 我的无线电台还在用
Yeah, my call sign, these days.
这位是俄克拉克 他是本地人
This is Aklark. He's our resident local boy.
嘿 马克 今天可真是不顺 是吧
Hey, Mac. I saw you came in a bit hectic there, huh?
是啊 有点
Yeah, just a little bit.
你们这是刚从狂欢节回来么？还是...
Did you guys just come from Burning Man, or...
感觉如何？伯特先生
How's it, Mr. Burt?
哇 加拿大的人都认识你
Wow! They even know you in Canada!
你没跟我提爆尾鸟的事啊
You failed to tell me about the AB infestation.
- 我们这儿有爆尾鸟？ - 对啊
- We have Ass Blasters? - Yeah.
这可不太正常啊 小姑娘
It ain't a polar bear, girl.
爹妈一定不相信的
Mom and Dad aren't gonna believe it.
爹妈？
"Mom and Dad"?
是时候叙旧了 甘莫先生
Here's a blast from the past, Mr. Gummer.
我是瓦尔和朗达的女儿
I'm Val and Rhonda's daughter.
不会吧 格拉波虫天启觉醒事件里的瓦尔和朗达
No! Val and Rhonda from the OG Graboid apocalypse?
不要思议吧 你就是特拉维斯吧
Crazy, huh? You must be Travis.
是的
I am.
嗯...这些年来我都没怎么跟你父母联系过
Uh... I kind of lost track of your parents over the years.
没关系 联系不到他们 尤其是瓦尔 很正常
It's okay. They're easy to lose track of, especially Val.
我们去科研站吧 大家都在等你
Let's get you back to the station. Everybody's waiting.
他本身就不愿跟人保持联系
He's not the keeping-in-touch type.
走吧
Come on.
天哪
Aw, man!
我看你这次来是全副武装啊 伯特先生
I see you've come up north loaded for bear, Mr. Burt.
是的 你这是拍明翰武器公司303式自动步枪吧 真不错
Yeah, BSA .303. Nice.
要对付绝大多数恶棍还是可以的
It'll kill most varmints.
是啊 不过要是拿这枪对付格拉波虫
Yeah, well, for the varmints we're hunting,
就像弹弓对付坦克一样
that's like shooting a slingshot at a Sherman tank.
我还以为这儿会有多冷呢
I thought it'd be colder than a reindeer's ball bag up here.
我们正处在一股北极热浪的中心
We're in the middle of an Arctic heat wave,
冰雪都在加速融化
which has greatly accelerated the snow melt.
天哪 这儿可真暖和
Hell, I'm hotter than a 50 cal on full auto!
甘莫先生 很高兴您能来
Mr. Gummer, glad you could make it.
欢迎您来到博伊特谷北极科研站
Welcome to the Bo顃e Canyon Arctic Research Station
您也可以像我们一样 叫它世界尽头科研站
or, like we used to call it, science at the edge of the world.
您是丽塔.西姆斯博士吧
You must be, uh, Dr. Rita Sims?
- 很高兴见到您 - 谢谢
- Good to meet you. - Yeah.
这位是弗里兹博士
This is Dr. Ferezze.
- 我是查尔斯.弗里兹 - 博士 你好
- Charles Ferezze. - Doc.
您旅途如何
How was your flight in?
呃 一点小麻烦
Well, let's just say, uh, we hit some chop.
我们的引擎坏了
We blew the engine.
实际上 我们受到爆尾鸟袭击了
Actually, we came under Ass Blaster attack,
在躲避中 飞机引擎烧毁了
and during the ensuing aerial dogfight, the engine was blown.
- 爆尾鸟？ - 是的
- An Ass Blaster? - Yeah.
引擎烧毁了
Blew the engine?
可是你还得用飞机送我们回去呀
But you have to fly me back to Montreal so I can report
向上级汇报最新情况呢
to the powers that be about the recent turn of events.
那只能等我把它修好后
Well, they'll just have to wait till I get this puppy airborne again.
可我等不及了
I can't stay here one more minute!
报歉 我去修引擎了
Excuse me. I've got an engine to fix.
抱歉
Excuse me.
弗里兹博士总是一惊一乍的
Dr. Ferezze, he startles at the drop of a feather.
抱歉我们还没互相介绍过
I'm sorry. We haven't met yet.
哦 他是特拉维斯.韦尔克
Oh, Travis Welker, my, uh...
我的...助手
My wing, uh... Wingman.
谢谢您前来
Thank you for coming.
我得进去查下情况
I've got to go inside, get the lay of the land.
日落竟然是在凌晨3点48分
Sunset at 3:48 a.m.
对呀 这儿可是午夜阳光的国度 韦尔克先生
Well, it's the Land of the Midnight Sun, Mr. Welker.
你是说太阳不会完全落山（跟我口交）
Are you saying that the sun is never going down on me?
对 太阳不会落到地平线以下
Well, it's never gonna go below the horizon,
如果你是这个意思的话
if that's what you're asking.
我们派了一支三人钻探队到那边山上的冰盖上
We sent a three-man drill team to the glacial field
离这儿大约有半天的路程
about a half a day up mountain from here.
三人全KIA
You have three KIA?
就是阵亡
Killed in action.
喂 这缩写哪能随便用
Whoa, that's a big 10-4, good buddy.
- 我是斯瓦克哈莫 - 你好
- Name's Swackhamer. - Swackhamer.
这地方就是我亲手建的
I hammered-and-nailed this place together.
你要有什么事找我就行
You need to know anything, I'm your guy.
三人中两人确认死亡 另一人推断死亡
There's two that we can verify dead, one assumed dead.
已确认？怎么确认的？
Verified? How?
根据现场情况判断的
Well, from the kill site.
丽塔和她的队友找到了一个头颅
Rita and her crew managed to recover a severed head,
一个被吃得只剩下一部分骨盆 还有一个吃了一半的睾丸
a partially eaten pelvis, and a half-eaten testicle.
你们是怎么找到那个吃了一半的睾丸的
How do you recover a half-eaten testicle?
那 这儿的雪怎么都不见了？西姆斯博士
Now, where's all the snow, Dr. Sims?
今年是北极地区有记录以来最温暖的一年
This year in particular has been one of the warmest on record up here.
这位是哈特.汉森先生 甘莫先生
Meet Hart Hansen, Mr. Gummer.
地貌学博士 毕业于剑桥大学
He's a PhD in Geomorphology from the University of Cambridge.
啊 对 玩飞机的那位
Ah, yeah, airplane boy.
是遥控机 算是个爱好吧
It's an RC. Kind of a hobby.
嗯...的确是个爱好
It's actually a habit, um...
好吧 我上瘾了 总之
Okay, it's an addiction. Anyway,
很高兴认识您 甘莫先生
it's a pleasure to meet you, Mr. Gummer.
相信您会发现从地质学角度来讲
I'm sure you'll find that Bo顃e Canyon
博伊特谷是个独特的存在
is a very unique geological phenomenon.
这儿的永久性冰冻苔原
This perennially frozen tundra is interrupted
被近10平方公里的融土地带分割开来
for approximately 10 square kilometers by thawed soil.
融土？外边是非常干燥的啊
Thawed? It's bone dry out there.
这里的融水温泉是地热能的典型体现
The Meltwater Hot Springs are a pleasant symptom
而地热则从地球内部
of geothermal heat, which warms the Earth from deep beneath the land
不断对我们脚下的土地加热
that we're standing on.
这样一来 爆尾鸟的存在就很合理了
That explains the ABs.
爆尾鸟
Ass Blasters!
- 爆尾鸟... - 你们以为很可笑吗
- Ass Blasters... - You think this is funny?
这些生物绝不能小看 它们就是杀人不眨眼的冷血机器
These creatures are no joke. They are all-go, no-quit killing machines.
我很抱歉你们失去了三位朋友
Now, I'm sorry for the loss of your friends,
但如果你们不照我说的做
but if you don't do exactly as I say,
伤亡一定会复现
they won't be the last to die around here.
这不好笑 我们懂了 甘莫先生
Not funny, Mr. Gummer. We get it.
离海拔永久冻土正在融化
The permafrost at a higher elevation is melting,
使得苔原生态系统更加脆弱 格拉波虫也就趁虚而入了
so the tundra is more easily breached. Ergo, Graboids.
你是说造成这次格拉波虫灾的
You're telling me melting ice caps and warmer temperatures
是冰盖的融化和升高的温度？
are causing this, uh, Graboid Arctic stampede?
差不多吧 但还有别的原因
Kind of, but there's more.
那我给你讲讲吧 到底为什么
Enlighten me. Why here?
因为进化 甘莫先生
Evolution, Mr. Gummer.
大自然教会我们一件事
There's one thing Nature has taught us,
那就是生物有能力拓展新领地
and that's life can expand into new territories.
或许这次的格拉波虫就是最原始的一批
Maybe these are the first Graboids.
- 对 就像是前前寒武纪 - 正是
- Yeah, like pre-Precambrian. - Exactly.
或许它们在几十亿年前 就向南迁移了数百万英里
And maybe they migrated south millions, maybe even billions of years ago
并进化为沙漠生物
and evolved into a desert creature.
如今 数十亿的冰冻沉眠后...
And now, after countless giga-annum lying dormant in ice...
它们醒了
They've awakened.
得了吧 这也太玄乎了吧
Come on, this sounds like a bunch of sassafras!
的确是这样的
It does sound sassafrassy!
西姆斯博士 能跟你私下说几句吗
Dr. Sims, a word?
还要多久才能修好
How much longer?
我得把进气歧管缝合好 修复汽化器
I've got to cold-stitch the intake manifold, rebuild the carb.
听着 如果你不赶紧把这些破玩意修好 我就...
Look, if you don't get this clunker in the air soon, I'll...
你就怎样？佛粒子博士
You'll what, Mr. Freeze?
是弗里兹 查尔斯.弗里兹博士
Ferezze. Dr. Charles Ferezze.
怎么了
What is it?
美国国防部高级研究计划局
DARPA.
他们在这里干什么
What are they doing here?
- 哦 他们么？！ - 嘘 小声点
- Oh, them? - Shh!
对 就是他们
Yes, them.
你跟他们什么关系
What's your association with them?
他们是我们邻居啊
They're our research neighbors.
我们干嘛要小声说话 他们又听不到
Why are we whispering? They can't hear us.
他们什么时候来的
When did they arrive?
几个月前
They arrived a couple of months ago.
他们在忙某些美加合作项目
They're working on some US-Canadian project.
高度机密
It's very hush-hush.
怎么了 什么事
Why? What?
一定是在搞生化武器吧
Bio-weapons is what.
我跟你打赌 我们现在正身处
I'll bet you a dollar to a donut hole we've zeroed in
美国国防部高级研究计划局的试验重地
on DARPA's testing ground.
你觉得我们邻居
You think that our research neighbors
在把那些怪虫当做生化武器喂养？
are breeding these creatures as bio-weapons?
正是 这儿就是屠杀场
Bingo! This is the killing ground,
而你们就是小白鼠
and you're the guinea pigs.
你可真说到点子上了
I think you're reaching.
越南战争期间 他们就拿海豚做了炸弹载体
It's a verifiable fact that DARPA started training dolphins
这都已经被证实了
as bomb-carriers during Vietnam.
而最近 他们正致力于将机械昆虫武器化
More lately, they've been outed for weaponizing cyborg insects.
所以不 我绝不会轻易相信这些黑衣人
No, ma'am, I wouldn't put anything past these black-hat Mengeles.
有爆尾鸟进入科研站了
We got Ass Blasters on campus!
弗里兹博士带着东西去外面了
Dr. Ferezze is out there with that thing.
哦 上帝 那个家伙真成了蠢蛋
Oh, Lord. That guy's turned into a real ass-ache.
那个AB上的20是什么
What's the 20 on that AB?
屋顶上有怪物在喷火
That flaming sphincter is on the roof!
摄像头 我们需要看到屋顶
Eyes! We need eyes on that roof!
我正打开屋摄像头
I'm bringing up the roof cam!
好吧 听好了
All right, listen up!
如果基地有可恶的爆尾鸟 那么格拉波虫也不远了
If there are Ass Blasters on station, Graboids aren't far behind.
它们对地面震动有反应 所以大家都别动
They respond to seismic vibrations, so everyone stay still.
弗雷泽博士 就是我想见的人
Dr. Ferezze. Just the man I wanted to see.
准备运送尸体留下的东西
The bodies, or what's left of them, are ready for transport.
还有时间吗？我们需要再次检查细节
When you have a minute, we need to go through the details again.
检查过了 这明显遭到了格拉波虫的攻击
We've been through it. It was an apparent Graboid attack.
格拉波虫吗？
Graboid?
锁定目标 上膛完毕
Locked and loaded.
那怪物把我们的通讯塔拆掉了
That thing just took down our comms tower.
可是我们没有说话
We've got no talk.
我们的数据链接和局域网也瘫痪了
Our data-link and NetCam are down, too.
那该死的家伙怎么跑出来的
How'd that ass-wipe get out there?
现在我要出去 保护他的屁股
Now I've got to save his sorry butt! I'm going outside.
你以前见过笨蛋吗
You ever seen an Ass Blaster before?
- 没有 - 哦
- Nope. - Yeah.
这是第一次
This is a first.
它们很酷 但很卑鄙而且臭气熏天
They're pretty cool, actually, but they're mean, and they stink.
我曾经交过这样的男朋友
I had a boyfriend like that once.
你单身吗
You single?
你想和我在一起试试吗
Are you trying to get sweet with me?
- 当然 - 不行
- Definitely. - It's not gonna work.
博士 博士
Doc! Doc!
博士 有点骨气
Doc! Grow a spine, huh?
看着我
Look at me.
我是个爷们 重复一遍
I have balls of steel. Say it!
我是个爷们
I have balls of steel.
我是个纯爷们
My balls are stainless steel!
我男子气概爆棚
My balls are in the Guinness Book of Balls!
好的 戴上这个
Right! You put this on.
- 好 - 它可以隐藏你的热信号
- Yes. - It'll hide your heat signature, huh?
现在 听着 你得像影子一样跟着我 听到没？
Now, look. You stick with me like a shadow. You hear that?
听到了
Yes.
现在 把你的老二放回你的裤子里
Now, put that dick back in your pants
- 跟着我做 - 遵命
- and do what I do, right? - Yes, sir.
- 罗杰 - 罗杰
- Roger? - Roger.
- 罗杰 我们走 - 好的
- Roger that. Let's go. - Okay.
来吧 伙计 戴上兜帽
Come on, soldier. Hoods up!
怎么回事？
What the hell?
笨蛋 来啊
Suck on this, bird brain!
走开 笨蛋
Go away, sucker!
甘莫先生 你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling, Mr. Gummer?
发生了什么
What's going on?
- 你刚做了手术 - 什么
- You just had surgery. - What?
关节内窥镜手术
Arthroscopic surgery. To remove a mondo tapeworm
去除您肠子里的蒙多绦虫
that was causing a cluster-fete in your intestines.
我知道 很恶心 对吧
I know. Gross, huh?
俄勒冈州 科瓦利斯 对吧
Oregon State. Corvallis, right?
是的 说对了
Yup. Go Beavers!
你知道吗？在我很小的时候
You know, my dad's been telling me stories about you
我父亲就向我讲述你的故事
since I could bounce on his knee and...
我还是不敢相信瓦尔.麦基是你父亲
I still can't believe Val McKee's your father!
他更像个爸爸 真的
He's more of a dad, really.
实际上是个疯狂的叔叔
Crazy uncle, actually.
很疯狂 对吧
Wild, huh?
你父亲是我见过的最聪明的人
Your father was the most brilliant underachiever lever met.
对 我妈妈也是这样说
Yeah. That's what Mom always says.
他总是告诉我你非常顽固
He always told me what a hard-ass you were.
对 非常固执
I mean, are.
哦 不 不可能 那是...
Oh, no way. No way! Are those...
格拉波虫的皮 是的 爸爸为妈妈做的
Graboid skin? Yeah. Dad made them for Mom.
妈妈把它们交给了人 坚不可摧
She handed them down to me. Pretty indestructible.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing up here?
实习 我正在攻读数学地球科学硕士学位
Internship. I'm doing my Masters in Mathematical Geosciences.
你感觉怎样 伯特
How are you feeling, Burt?
说起来不尽如意
Speaking of underachievers.
我只有平时的五分之一 伙计
I am as strong as a fifth of whiskey, Wingman.
真的？因为你恢复得比较慢
Really? 'Cause you looked slower than the Mississippi out there.
我的弹药 我的战斗背心 我的衣服叱
Where's my munitions, my combat vest, my clothes, huh?
在你左边
To your left.
嗯 感觉好多了吧 甘莫先生
Well, feel better, Mr. Gummer.
好吧 谢谢你麦基小姐
All right. Thank you, Miss McKee.
你可以叫我瓦尔
You can call me Val.
你怎么了 伯特
What's going on with you, Burt?
在球场上摔跤一点也像你
It's not like you to take a knee on the field.
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
你在哪买到的HK91步枪
Where'd you get that HK91?
打扰一下 甘莫先生
Mr. Gummer?
你需要看一些东西
There's something that you need to see.
和上次测量相比 水位下降了15cm
The water levels dropped 15 centimeters since our last measurement.
在样品的土壤气体中发现了一种新的化学元素
The samples have detected a new chemical element in the soil gas.
能确定它是什么吗？
Can you determine what it is?
嗯..计算机把它读成HCO2H
Uh... The computer's reading it as HCO2H.
甲酸？
Formic acid?
对
Yeah.
而且是高浓缩的剂量
Yeah, and it's a highly concentrated dose.
PH值的酸度已经下降了
The acidity in the pH is off the charts.
那是什么鬼东西
What the hell was that?
你听到了吗
You hear that?
快走 现在就出去
Get out! Get out now!
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell?
那是什么
What is it?
你已经被感染了 甘莫先生
You've been infected, Mr. Gummer,
被一种寄生生物感染
by what appears to be a parasitic organism that is
它的破坏性强而且潜伏期长
quite hostile and has an extremely slow gestation.
坏消息是什么
What's the bad news?
非常不幸 它在某一成熟阶段会分泌一种神经毒素
Well, unfortunately, it secretes a neurotoxin at a certain maturation,
杀死宿主
killing the host.
杀死宿主？你是说伯特是宿主吗？
Killing the host? You mean, Burt being the host?
我们已经鉴定出这种毒素来自于格拉波虫
We've identified the toxin as originating from a Graboid.
格拉波虫吗？
A Graboid?
- 见鬼.. - 听我说
- What... - Just indulge me.
脑炎引起的眼睛出血
Blood behind the eye caused by cerebral inflammation.
晚期 情况很糟
Advanced stage. It's not good.
你需要抗体
You're gonna need antibodies.
我们怎么得到它们
Well, how do we get them?
从格拉波虫那里
From a Graboid.
也许我们可以在血库停下去抓一只
Maybe we can get one to stop by the blood bank.
你到底是怎么被格拉波虫病毒感染的？
How the hell did you get infected by a Graboid?
被它吞进肚子里
I was in the belly of the beast.
好了 我们杀了一只格拉波虫 搞定了
Okay, so we kill a Graboid. We get it done.
我来吧 伯特
I got this, Burt.
这些抗体需要从活的格拉波虫中提取出来才能存活
The antibodies need to be extracted from a live Graboid to be viable.
活的格拉波虫
A live Graboid?
不可能
Impossible.
你打算用套索套住它的脖子吗
You plan on throwing a lasso over its neck?
抱歉 我需要做一个周界扫描
If you'll excuse me, I need to do a perimeter sweep.
我想你还不明白你的状况有多紧急
I don't think you understand the urgency of your condition.
不要让我的情况妨碍到重要的事
Don't let the urgent get in the way of the important.
您的身体在衰竭 甘莫先生
Your body is failing, Mr. Gummer.
胡扯 我想做二次诊断
Bullshit! I want a second opinion.
我知道 所有一切都显示你有男子气概
Yeah, I know that's all macho and everything, Burt,
但我更关心你的健康
but I happen to care about your health!
关心别的地方吧
Go care someplace else.
说什么胡话
That's a dick thing to say.
没有病毒能逍遥法外
No bad seed shall go unpunished!
把它从我身上拿开
Get it off of me!
抓紧
Hang on.
请不要松手
Please don't let go!
- 抓紧 - 请不要松手
- Hold on! - Don't let go!
- 天哪 - 求你了 别松手
- My God! - Please, don't let go!
- 求你了 别松手 - 我抓住你的
- Please, don't let go. - I got you.
- 抓紧我 抓紧我 - 该死 我抓住你的
- Hold me! Hold me! - Shit! I got you.
不
No!
好了 封锁窗口
All right! Block that window!
好了 各位 都系好颌带
Okay, everyone, buckle your chinstraps
然后打包一块肉三明治 我们受到了攻击
and pack a meat sandwich! We are under attack.
关严所有车门和车窗
Secure all doors and windows!
天 真棒
Well, this is just great.
我们被一种凶猛的地下生物攻击
We're under attack by a hostile underground life form.
我们要死了
We're all going to die!
听我说 博士
Listen to me, Doc.
取出几汤匙水泥
Take a couple of tablespoons of cement
把它硬化 嗯？
and harden the hell up, huh?
好了 听着 有武器的人把它装上
Okay, look, anybody with a weapon, load it up.
我们的棍子很得力 无论什么时候都能用到它
We have the sharp end of the stick. Whatever you got, use it!
牛仔女孩 放松点
Easy, there, cowgirl!
我没法让地震监视器运行
I can't get this seismic vibration monitor working.
我们的数据链和网络摄像头都坏了 甘莫先生
Our data-link and NetCam are down, Mr. Gummer.
昨晚那只爆尾鸟把我们的通讯塔拆掉了
Yeah, the Ass Blaster tore our comms tower apart last night.
你能修好吗？
Can you fix it?
斯瓦克哈莫整个上午都在研究这个问题 但是...
Swackhamer's been working on it all morning, but...
高频天线完全损坏了 同轴电缆被切断了
The HF antenna's totally destroyed. Coax has been severed.
网格盒也被击中了
The grid pack dish is totally shot.
好吧 多久能修好
All right, how long will it take to fix?
- 至少一天 - 好吧
- A day, at least. - All right.
铱星卫星电话
Iridium satellite phone?
- 谁拿走了卫星电话 - 我之前见弗里兹博士拿过
- Who took the sat phone? - I saw Dr. Ferezze with it earlier.
哦 费雷泽逃走了
Oh, Ferezze flew the coop.
找到他 尽快给我打电话
All right, find him and get that sat phone to me ASAP!
这是我们唯一的救命稻草 我们必须打电话给疏散中心
It's our lifeline out of here. We've got to call in Evac
让这些孩子到安全的地方
and get these kids someplace safe!
我可在800码处投弹
I can drop an elk at 800 yards
并在30分钟内把怪物处理好
and field dress it in less than 30 minutes.
这样你就不用担心了
Maybe that'll pull you out of your worry well.
我们准备好了 甘莫先生
We're up for this, Mr. Gummer.
收到 麦基小姐
Copy that, Miss McKee.
试着做吧 目标是格拉波虫
We are flying blind. Advantage, Graboid.
西姆斯博士 我从来没有正确地了解过这片土地的情况
I was never properly briefed on the lay of the land, Dr. Sims.
我们在这个位置
We are here.
我们的四周都是高山
There are mountains to our east, west, north, and south.
这是一个真正的地道峡谷
It's a true box canyon.
完全的地理隔离 太好了
Total geographic isolation. D閖?freaking-vu!
这是工棚 这是美国国防部高级研究计划局的营地
This is the bunkhouses. That's DARPA encampment.
飞机库在我们前方大约120m
The hangar's about 120 meters to our direct front.
阿弗拉克在它下方
Aflac's down there.
是阿克拉克
It's Aklark!
做点有用的事 温曼 向飞机库呼救
Make yourself useful, Wingman. Give the hangar a holler.
用什么 杯子和绳子吗
With what, a cup and a string?
用对讲机
Use the walkie-talkie.
哟 北极星一号 这里是北极星基地 收到了吗
Yo, North Star One, this is North Star Base. You copy?
收到了老兄 北极星一号 回复你的方位 结束
You got Mac, North Star One. Send your traffic. Over.
听着 把它关掉 好吗？
Look, shut it down now, all right?
停止所有工作并呆在里面
Stop all work and stay inside.
- 这是什么？ - 一条路
- What's this? - A road.
你是说这条崎岖不平的路？已经走不了了
You mean washboard. The road's out.
去年冬天塌方 完全走不了了
Landslide last winter. It's totally impassable.
整个基地就像是格拉波虫的开阔野原
This whole base is like open range for a Graboid.
等一下 你现在告诉我
Wait a second. You're telling me
我们在死亡地带中间没有出路了
we're smack dab in the middle of a kill zone and no way out?
大家不要动
Everybody freeze!
瓦尔
Valerie.
我想它要走了
I think it's leaving.
不
No.
它被另一种震动吸引了
It's caught wind of another vibration.
有东西在动
Something's moving.
或者是个人
Or someone.
我在工棚里没找到弗里兹博士
I can't find Dr. Ferezze in the bunkhouse.
那个擅离职守的混蛋又去哪了？
That cheese-dick gone AWOL again?
oh
Oh!
天哪
Jeez.
弗里兹博士
Dr. Ferezze!
哈特 不
Hart, no!
回来 别傻傻地跟着傻瓜
Back here! Don't follow stupid with stupid.
弗里兹博士
Dr. Ferezze!
回来弗里兹博士
Come back, Dr. Ferezze!
弗里兹博士 你要去哪
Dr. Ferezze, where are you going?
除了这里 哪都行
Anywhere but here!
冷静点 想想 弗里兹博士
Just calm down and think, Dr. Ferezze.
除了这 你别无他处
There's nowhere for you to go!
我要碰碰运气
I'll take my chances.
- 哈特 - 它来了
- Hart! - Here it comes!
弗里兹博士 拜托 别这样
Dr. Ferezze! Please, don't do this!
别发动汽车
Don't start the car!
- 拜托 - 走了 朋友
- Please! - Hasta luego, amigo.
弗里兹博士
Dr. Ferezze!
该死 我子弹空了
Damn, I don't have a shot!
弗里兹博士
Dr. Ferezze!
进去 所有人 马上 快走
Inside! Everyone, now! Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
该死的东西是真的
This shit just got real!
我不敢想象那个怪物会对弗里兹博士做什么
I can't believe what that thing did to Dr. Ferezze.
这些怪物刚从冬眠中醒来 根据它们瓣身体质量指数
They just came out of hibernation and, based on their body mass index,
它们需要吃很多东西
those creatures need to eat a lot.
- 有多少 - 很难说
- How many are there? - It's impossible to tell...
没有地震监测仪
without my seismic vibration monitor.
我们不能呆在这儿
Well, we can't stay here.
明白 我们的武器还不够对付这些怪物
Copy that. We've got weapons, but not enough for these bad boys.
那就见招拆招吧
The bigger the problem, the bigger the hammer.
是吗？你有什么想法
Yeah? What've you got in mind?
飞机库中有一些炸药
There's a couple of cases of dynamite in the hangar.
还有汽油 工具和其他零碎的东西
Petrol, tools, bear bangers, odds and ends.
有足够的东西可以引爆炸药 我们可以把炸弹塞进它们的喉咙
There's enough stuff to MacGyver a bomb we can stuff down their throats!
它们吃了会怎样不关我们的事
Sounds like that's our FOB.
还有一个问题
One problem.
飞机库的地板被压实了
The hangar's got a compacted chip-stone floor.
来吧 伙计 他们会上钩的
Oh, come on, man. They're gonna be like
像鲨鱼咬住苹果一样
sand sharks bobbing for apples.
嗯 然后我们就成了被咬的红富士牌苹果
Yeah, and we'll be the Granny Smiths.
地板有1.2m厚
This floor is 1.2 meters above the ground,
由钢铁结构支撑
supported by a steel substructure.
那些东西无法击倒这个地方
Those things won't be able to knock this place down.
不 这只是时间问题
Yeah, but it's only a matter of time
只是在他们冲过地板并且吃掉我们的午餐之前
before they come blasting through the floor and eat our lunch.
我有个主意 发电机在机库对吗
I've got an idea. The generator's in the hangar, right?
是的 三相电源 63-amp电缆
Yeah. Triple-phase power, 63-amp cables.
根据这些图纸
According to these blueprints,
这个机库有一个深桩基础
this hangar's got a deep-pile foundation.
是的 钢铁沉箱直接进入基岩
Yeah, steel caissons going directly into the bedrock.
我自己钻的
Drilled it myself.
你认为你可以重铺设电力 这样它就能进入钢铁沉箱吗？
You think you can re-route the power so it goes to the steel caissons?
你说的是我想的这样吗
Are you saying what I'm thinking?
你想的是什么
What are you thinking I'm saying?
我想的是我们注入电流
I'm thinking that you're saying that we shoot a dose of milliamps
直接进入地下水并创造某种
straight into the groundwater and create some kind of...
- 地下电栅栏？- 没错
- Underground electrical fence. - Exactly.
这正是我说的而也是你在想的 你能做到吗？
That's exactly what I'm saying you're thinking. Can you do it?
我可是事半功倍的
I've done more with less.
是啊 但如果不奏效 我们就死定了
Yeah, but if it doesn't work, we die.
那到底是什么 伯特 你有把果冻钉在墙上过吗
So what the hell, Burt? Have you ever nailed Jell-O to a wall?
我不知道这有什么关系
I'm not sure how that's relevant.
这很重要 因为我做到了
It's relevant because I did it.
你猜怎么着 它卡住了
And guess what? It stuck.
你知道为什么吗？因为每个人都说我不行
You know why? Because everyone said I couldn't.
好的 我明白了 我知道了
All right, I got it. I got it!
我有一个计划 我们去机库
And we've got a plan. We're off to the hangar.
分成两队 特拉维斯 你和西姆斯博士
Teams of two. Travis, you, and Dr. Sims.
斯瓦克哈莫 你和我一队
Swackhamer, you're with me.
温曼 我们需要转移视线
Wingman, we're gonna need a diversion!
我懂
I'm on it.
我要假装我没听到你把我漏掉了？
I'm gonna pretend I didn't just hear you leave me out
因为我努力的加入这次蠕虫狩猎
because I'm coming on this worm hunt.
厄尔猎人 是吗？你会用这个小短腿吗？
Elk hunter, huh? Think you can bang on this short arm?
小意思 你想要让它可控还是想让它变成一个危险的游戏？
Piece of cake. You zero that scope for distance or dangerous game?
- 你认为呢？ - 这是个垃圾问题
- What do you think? - Stupid question.
介意我调整成我喜欢的模式吗
Mind if I tweak it for my preferred point of impact?
我爸和我总是把我们的望远镜瞄准在100码高2.5英寸的地方
Dad and I always zeroed our scopes at 2.5 inches high at 100 yards.
可以 随便
Well, whatever floats your boat.
你来看守 带上瓦加斯 到屋顶上
You're on overwatch. Take Vargas and go on the roof.
好的
Roger that.
抓紧了吗？它要踢你了
And hold on tight, huh? She'll kick some!
放心吧
Got you.
要枪还是瓦斯
The gun or Vargas?
老头子 感觉如何？
You feel up for this, old man?
还行
I'm fine.
准备好
You make ready.
好的 你准备好了吗？西姆斯博士
Okay, you ready, Dr. Sims?
靠 看谁来了
Oh, shit. Look what the cat dragged in.
- 哦 真棒 你在这里 - 卡茨先生
- Oh, good. You're here. - Mr. Cutts.
我刚刚在融水温泉失去了我的顶尖科学家
I just lost my top scientist at the Meltwater Hot Springs.
你没有他你就力不从心了吗？
You just got in over your head and had to punt, huh?
你的实验简直是胡作非为
Your experiment's run amok.
我的实验？
My experiment?
什么？你觉得是我在控制这些…
What, you think I'm actually controlling these...
是啊当然是你在控制 你的心理测试告诉我们
Yeah, but of course you would. Your psych eval suggested as much.
你有我的档案吗
You had me profiled?
很抱歉让你失望了 但这不是莫罗博士的岛
I'm sorry to disappoint you, but this is not the Island of Dr. Moreau.
我不是那种道德败类
I'm not some kind of walking ethical dumpster fire.
我在这里的使命比这更崇高
My mission here is more elevated than that.
哦 是啊 没有美国国防部高级研究计划局的讨厌鬼在这里工作 是吧
Oh, yes. No DARPA skunk works in the hopper, huh?
也许是没有生物工程 或是一小段格拉波虫的转基因
No bio-engineering perhaps? A little Graboid gene-splicing?
你知道 这是个好主意 但我不想要生物武器
You know, that's a good idea, but bio-weapons are not my thing.
我和一个工程团队在这儿
I'm here with an engineering team
评估地下水的纯度
to assess the purity of the groundwater
设计一个地下蓄水层 将水从北极运到文明世界
and to design an aquifer to move it out of the Arctic and into civilization.
这是关于水的吗
This is about water?
水是新的能源 你可能已经注意到
Water is the new oil, and, as you may have noticed,
北极现在有丰富的资源
the Arctic has it in abundance now.
现在只出现了其中一种生物
It took just one of those creatures
不到一分钟就杀了我最好的科学家
less than a minute to kill my best scientist.
都别动！都别动
Nobody move! Nobody move.
它在地板下面
It's under the floor.
别动
Don't move.
嘘！
Shh!
让我下去
Let me unload.
好
All right.
开火！
Fire at will!
耶！
Yes!
救我！救我！
Help! Help me!
Here!
救我！救我！
Help me! Help me!
好的 我们快走 开枪！
All right. Let's scoot and shoot!
那我们呢？
What about us?
北星一号到北星机库
North Star One to North Star Hangar.
我们在向你走来 结束
We are coming your way. Over.
明白 甘莫先生
Roger that, Mr. Gummer.
听起来好像是你踩在上面了
Sounds like you stepped in it up there.
肯定的 是时候深入了解一波了 一起干起来 结束
Affirmative. Time to dig in, work together. Over.
这是狩猎聚会？
Is it a hunting party?
当然 这可不是什么小马秀！
Sure as hell ain't no pony show!
好吧 听着 我要把它从这里引开
All right, look, I'm gonna lead it away from here.
我开始的时候 你们就跑！
When I do, run!
好！
Yeah!
像狗看到骨头一样
Like a dog to a bone!
生物力学是如此迷人!
Bio-mechanics are so sexy!
去机库！
To the hangar!
快点！
Come on!
前进！三点钟方向！
Incoming! Three o'clock!
靠！不是另一只！
Oh, shit! Not another one!
上卡车！
The truck!
- 斯瓦克哈莫 快起来！ - 好
- Swackhamer, get up! - Yeah.
快！在卡车里！
Come on! In the truck!
快！
Come on!
它扯住了我的裤子！
That thing's got me by the pants!
那就脱了你的裤子！
So take off your pants!
我死都不要！
100% no!
- 脱了你的裤子 丽塔！ - 不！
- Take off your pants, Rita! - No!
- 快脱了！靠！ - 不！
- Take them off now, goddammit! - No!
- 为什么？ - 我底下什么都没穿！
- Why? - I'm not wearing any underwear!
你是要去北极突击队吗
You're going commando in the Arctic?
我底下什么都没穿
I don't wear underwear.
这可是限制级的
It's too restricting.
- 我想我会喜欢！ - 是吗？
- I think I love! - Yeah?
- 嘿 哈特 - 嗯
- Hey, Hart? - Yeah?
你今天喝了多少能量饮料
How many of those energy drinks did you have today?
七罐吧
Six, maybe seven.
我的意思是可能是八罐
I mean, could be eight.
准备好开跑 温曼
Get ready to run, Wingman.
我们正在执行第二个转移策略
We're executing Diversion Tactic Two.
好的 哈特 是时候为队里拿个虫头了
Okay, Hart. Time to take one for the team.
脱裤子 让大虫咬
Free Willy and let the big dog eat.
你认真的？你想让我这么做？
Seriously? You want me to drop trou?
不要质疑我的命令！
Don't question my orders!
现在 你拿出你的丁丁来甩！
Now, you take out that disco stick, and let it dance!
好吧 不要任何人看
Okay. Don't anybody look.
老兄！我们有更大的虫子咬操心了！
Dude! We have bigger worms to worry about!
准备重新部署！
Get ready to redeploy!
那是男孩的游戏！
That boy's got game!
准备开火！
Fire at will!
- 最好今天！ - 我在努力！
- Preferably today! - I'm trying!
哦 快！如果你要像小狗一样撒尿 就呆在上面
Oh, come on! If you're gonna piss like a puppy, stay on the porch.
我不是小狗 甘莫先生 我会告诉你的
I'm no puppy, Mr. Gummer. I'll tell you that.
给我造一个方舟
Gonna build me an ark!
我们很清楚机库在哪儿 走！走！走！
We're clear to the hangar. Go! Go! Go!
坏消息 瓦尔 十一点钟方向
Bad news, Val. Eleven o'clock!
这次格拉波虫变成两个了
That makes the Graboid count two.
是的 两个活着 一个死了
Yeah, two alive. One dead.
伯特？
Burt, you copy? Over?
你在吗？请回答？
You there? Copy?
伯特？
Burt?
收到 温曼
Copy, Wingman.
你还好吗
You doing okay?
我能怎样
Why the hell wouldn't I be?
我们在打一堆格拉波虫
We're fighting a Graboid apocalypse
和一群军士！
with a bunch of noncoms!
别担心我！
Don't worry about me!
就行任务就是
Just stick to the mission objective.
我们得赶紧把这些虫子弄进去！
We've got to get one of those worms pronto!
小心！朝你过去了！
Watch out! It's headed your way!
从钻塔进来了
Incoming. From the drill tower.
祈祷吧 我要打开这个小闸门了
Say a prayer, I'm gonna flip the switch on this ittle cucarcha.
一！二！
One! Two!
三！
Three!
靠！
Shit!
小心！
Watch out!
它还活着 它还在动！
It's working. It's actually working!
它过不来
It can't get through.
我跟你说过我可是事半功倍的！
I told you I've done more with less!
快！哇！我的妈！
Come on! Whoo! Yeah!
你还好吗 伯特？
How're you doing out there, Burt?
讲话啊
Talk to me.
伯特 你还活着吗？
Burt, you're alive?
老头子 你一生中从未放弃过任何东西啊
You've never given up on anything in your life, old man.
别现在放弃啊
Don't start now!
你的父亲状况不容乐观 啊 特拉维斯
You father is very sick, Travis.
他不能死 至少不是现在 在没有我的注视下
He can't die. Not now. Not on my watch.
这是他第二次神经肌肉崩溃
This is his second neuro-muscular collapse.
加油 特拉维斯
Come on, Travis.
快起来
Man up.
好了 看 我们抓住了其中一个对吧
Okay, look, we capture one of these things, right?
怎样得到我们要的
How do we get what we need?
喉咙里应该有一个腺囊
There should be a glandular sac somewhere in the throat.
看来莎莉在测试我们的地下电栅栏
Looks like Sally's testing our underground electrical fence.
谁是莎莉
Who's Sally?
你给它取得名字？
You named it?
这是一个前任的名字
After an ex.
莎莉 灵魂毁灭者
Sally Soulsmasher.
她是一个肮脏的 吃人的婊子
She was a dirty, man-eating bitch
曾经把她的脸贴在不属于她的地方
who used to stick her nose where it didn't belong.
一切都好吧
Everything okay out there?
收到 长官 把门锁上 结束
Copy that, sir. Just locking the gate. All clear.
不要动 你这个傻瓜
Stop moving, you idiot.
它在穿过地板！
It's coming through the floor!
温曼？
Wingman?
温曼 你在吗?
Wingman, you there?
伯特 你怎么样了？
Burt. How are you feeling?
好的很
Fit as a butcher's dog.
我去找你 温曼
I'm coming your way, Wingman!
我们走 伙计们 我们走 去干它一场
Let's go, guys. Let's go. Let's get to work.
斯瓦克哈莫 开炸吧
Swackhamer, start making those bombs.
- 看 伯特 我们… - 灭了这些恶魔！
- Look, Burt, we... - Got to destroy these devils!
- 不 我们的得抓住其中一个！ - 我们不抓了 都杀掉！
- No, we have to catch one of these! - We don't catch. We kill!
- 即使它杀了你 - 这不关我的事
- Even if it kills you? - This is not about me.
- 是 不关你的事！ - 如果我们拿到格拉波虫就不一样了
- Yes, it is! - Not if we still got Graboids out there.
得了 伯特 我只是想了解你
Come on, Burt. I'm just getting to know you.
我不想看到你可怜的死
I don't wanna see your sorry ass die.
挡我说我死了 我就死了
I'll be dead when I say I'm dead!
然而并不是这样！
That's not how this works!
据我所知 你不是这里下命令的
Last I checked, you don't give the orders around here.
哦 我现在是了
Oh, I do now.
你从来不回答我的问题
You never answered my question.
你在哪拿到的HK91
Where'd you get that HK91?
前妻 伯特
Ex-wife, Burt.
谁给你权利干涉我的事
Who gave you the right to meddle in my affairs?
嘿！我是你的某件事的结果 记得吗
Hey! I'm the result of one of your affairs, remember?
靠！靠！
Bullshit! Bullshit!
你不要把我绕进这场谈话！
You're not hooking and reeling me into this conversation!
我猜我碰到了他的软肋
I guess I touched his thermostat.
你想死吗？恩？是不是？
You wanna die? Huh? Do you?
别那么固执
Stop being so stubborn.
靠！
Damn!
你是不是…
Did you...
事史说忽悠吗
Did you say hooking and reeling?
天啊 伯特 你真是个天才
Jesus, Burt, you are a genius.
嘿 麦克 我们在飞机上做这个怎么样
Hey, Mac, how are we doing on that plane?
好 我得在拧几个螺丝
Well, I've got to put a wrench to a few more screws.
各位
Everybody, listen up.
我想我有办法抓住这些东西！
I think I've got a way we can catch one of these things!
怎么了？
What the hell is that?
地震警报
The seismic alarm.
我们为今天的汽车设定了核心样品钻探 记得吗
We set the core sample drilling on auto for today, remember?
那个该死的钻井塔就想格拉波虫的猫薄荷
That damn drilling tower is like Graboid catnip.
那只猫已经上钩了
That puss has already taken the bait.
好吧 如果我们不能把它关掉 我们就得让格拉波虫离开哈特
Okay, if we can't turn it off, we've got to lead that Graboid away from Hart.
我得把钻机关掉
I've got to shut off the drill rig.
你不能下去瓦尔
You can't go down there, Val.
战斗队形！弄一些噪音！
Battle stations! Let's make some noise!
这次把电压加倍 我要他死！
Double the voltage this time. I want him dead!
坚持住 哈特 我来了！
Hold on, Hart. I'm coming!
快点 瓦尔 来了两只虫子
Hurry up, Val. Number two's coming right at you.
来！来！来！燥起来！
Go! Go! Go! Raise Cain!
来爸爸这儿！
Come to papa!
斯瓦克哈莫！
Swackhamer!
哇！
Yeah!
断你的路！要你的命！
That'll close the carpool lane!
闯进了这个错误的机库 不是吗 你这个混蛋
Broke into the wrong goddamn hangar, didn't you, you bastard?
瓦尔 就在你前面
Val, it's in front of you!
我们走吧 哈特 撤退！
Let's go, Hart. It's retreating!
跳！
Jump!
快！
Come on!
好吧 让我们不要一团糟的庆祝 伙计们
All right, let's not celebrate in a huddle, folks.
外面只好还有一个格拉波虫
We've still got at least one Graboid out there.
哦 伙计们
Uh, guys,
我讨厌在打孔碗里放一个烂泥 但是这个杰妮得被炸了！
I hate to drop a turd in the punch bowl, but the genny's blown!
这是什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
没有地下电子围栏了
No underground electrical fence.
我们必须送他去医院
We've got to get him to medical.
好 你去发动飞机 随时待命！
Okay. Get that airplane ready to fly, and wait for my call.
好了 各位我准备好了
All right, everybody, I'm on the point.
有异常吗？
Any movement?
没有
Nothing. Zip.
- 小人物 - 纳达·木乔
- Zilch. - Nada mucho.
- 我们跑过去 更快到那 - 行吗？
- I say we run, get there fast. - Yeah.
要是怪物来了 我也无所畏惧
If that thing attacks, I'll just honey badger the shit out of it.
救命啊 这里
Uh, help? Over here!
啊 他居然活着？我没做错什么 对吧？
Oh, shit, he lived? I've got to do the right thing, don't I?
我们应该过去
It's a good habit to start.
好吧 丽塔 你带阿克拉克和伯特去治疗
Okay, Rita, you take Aklark and Burt to the medical.
不管你怎么做 保住他们的命
I don't care what you have to do to keep him alive!
斯瓦克 你跟我来
Swackhamer, you're with me.
数到三 我们就冲 一、二、三 快冲
On three, we break. One, two, three, break!
能见到你们真开心 快把我弄下去
Man, am I glad to see you guys now! Get me down from here.
跳下来 胆小鬼
Jump, you chicken-shit!
不不不 不要跳
No,no,no. Don't jump, okay?
让我告诉你你该咋办
But I'll tell you what you can do.
你得去除古莫先生之前27年的税收留置权
Remove all the tax liens on Mr. Gummer for the last 27 years
归还他的房子
and give him back his house,
否则我就让你留在这里
and I'll make sure that you stay on this side of the tundra.
行 怎样都行 成交
Yeah, whatever. Done.
哦 不不不 我们可还没完
Uh, no, we're not done.
我们余生都不想交税了
We also don't wanna pay taxes for the rest of our life.
联邦税还是州税的？对了 内华达州没有州税
Federal or state, yeah. Nevada doesn't have state taxes.
好 以后没有联邦税了
Yeah, no federal taxes!
行 可那很难操作
Well, that's gonna be a hard one to swing.
行 那你就呆在上面吧 不 不 行
Uh, have a nice life! Okay, yeah, yeah, yeah, fine.
- 都照你说的办 - 混蛋 你没看见梯子呀
- I'll do it. - You didn't see the ladder, asshole?
兄弟 小心点
Dude! Baby bag.
胆小鬼 要是你还有一丢丢的胆量
Hey, candy-ass! If you have a set of balls,
现在就用用吧
now would be the time to use them.
好
Yeah.
怪物在那 我们可以狂轰滥炸了
There she blows. Time for some psy ops.
我去分散他的注意力
I'm gonna distract Sally Soulsmasher with some shock and awe!
来吧 小虫怪
Suck on this, worm!
来吧
Come on!
喔！
Whoo!
耶！
Yeah!
燥起来
Ride them, cowboy!
现在感觉还好吗？
How do you like me now?
天啦 别让我呆在这
Oh, good. Get me out of here.
- 伯特 别紧张 - 不要对我说别紧张
- Take it easy, Burt. - Don't tell me to take it easy.
现在是情况报告时间
It's time for a sit rep.
好赶紧给我说说你的情况
Yeah, I think you better sit this rep out.
- 谁说听你的了 - 你说的
- Who put you in charge? - You did.
- 我说的？ - 是啊 你受伤时说的伯特
- I did? - Yeah, once you got hurt, Burt.
不管你愿不愿意 是你说的让我负责的
That puts me in charge whether you like it or not.
我还好
I feel fine.
叫大家做好准备
Tell everybody to gear up and get ready.
准备啥？
Get ready for what?
准备救你啊 蠢蛋
Ready to save your ass, that's what!
抓格拉波虫么
Capturing a Graboid! Right?
该死的 你在那是 为什么不告诉雨不要干呢？
Hell, while you're at it, why don't you tell the rain not to dry?
我是你唯一的机会
I'm your only shot.
- 就你? - 是啊 我
- You? - Yeah, me, Burt! Me!
你的任务是保护我的 东西
Your job is to preserve my legacy!
我的任务是做最后那个站着对抗那些北极格拉波虫
My job is to make a last stand against these Arctic Graboids.
你站不住的
You can't stand, Colonel Custer!
- 回去吧 - 他不属于你
- Back off! - It doesn't belong to you!
寒冷 残肢 是这些吗 伯特？
Cold, dead hands, is that it, Burt?
你怎么了？
What is wrong with you?
我试着在这里保护你 你固执的老傻瓜
I'm trying to save your bacon here, you stubborn old coot.
你越界了
You've crossed the line!
与你的战斗已经完结
This fight is done with you.
是吗？我可没完
Yeah, well, I'm not done with it!
不 你已经结束了
Yeah, you are.
不要让我手无寸铁
Don't leave me unarmed.
给你
There.
你有了真整坚实的靠山
You got your true love back.
我想血液肯定不比弹药厚 对吧 伯特
I guess blood ain't thicker than ammo, is it, Burt?
那是
Yeah.
要是你菊花能放炮 你就能战胜格拉波虫
If you've got Ass Blasters, you have Graboids.
是的 兄弟
That's right, soldier.
这是FOB.DOA
This is FOB. DOA.
TMZ
TMZ.
我的胆量足够进吉尼斯纪录
My balls are in the Guinness Book of Balls!
那不错
That went well!
哦 听起来像那么回事
Yeah, it sounded like it.
准备好了吗
You ready?
这很适合你
It's a good look for you.
我觉得那只大虫还在某个地方睡大觉吧
I guess the big boy's still out there sleeping somewhere.
真希望就他一只了
I hope he's the only one.
当你被推入时 你必须游泳 对吧？
When you get pushed in, you've got to swim, right?
嘿 汇报现在的情况
Hey, Swackhamer, sit rep?
等等
Seconds away!
特拉维斯 这个计划
Travis, this plan, it's
真他妈疯狂
fricking crazy, huh?
是啊 兄弟
Yeah, bro.
这是麦克 我五分钟后出发
This is Mac. I'm wheels up in five!
带我回到我的旗帜 拖沓的日子
Takes me back to my banner-tow days.
希望她能担此重任
Hope the old girl can handle the load.
不用担心 这只是一个简单的抓捕任务
Don't worry. Come on. It's just a pure catch-and-release mission!
鱼上钩了 你就归我了
When the fish is on, you want me
恨恨地拉起来 做一个摆渡 呃？
to pull up hard and do a wingover, eh?
确定 我们要用怪物的动力来降落她
Affirmative. We're gonna use the bitch's momentum to land her.
就看你的了
Okay, Aklark, she's all yours.
注意保持平衡我不想惊动怪物
Just keep it steady. We don't wanna wake the beast up.
伙计们
Dude!
开始行动
Let's go fishing.
好了瓦莱丽 你准备好收拾这些调皮的孩子了么
All right, Valerie, you ready to take down one of these bad boys?
早就准备好了
I'm so ready.
好嘞
All right!
等我就位了 就摇这个篮子
When I get in position, rock the cradle.
我再拿鱼钩
I'm baiting the hook.
好的瓦尔 准备好 它醒了
Okay, Val, get ready. It's awake.
只有三百米了
Three hundred meters and closing!
- 一百米 - 好的 行动
- One hundred meters and closing. - Okay, let's go.
快来 麦克 带她进来 带她进来
All right, Mac, bring her in. Bring her in.
哦 不是吧
Oh, shit.
哦 不
Hooked!
放 放
Release! Release!
现在情况如何
What now?
哈利路亚
Halle-freaking-lujah!
好了 听着 绝对不可以开枪 懂了吧
All right, listen, listen. Absolutely no guns, okay?
我们不想杀掉它 我们要活捉它
We don't wanna kill it. We want it alive.
我们对待这个东西太老派
We're going old-school on this thing.
公平对阵 可以
Shirts versus skins, all right?
- 一个三的铁？ - 这是我能做的最好的事
- A three iron? - It was the best I could do.
好的
All right.
用A计划对付它
Let's go Alpha on this worm!
好
Okay.
哇哦
All right.
真棒
Come on.
捉住他 快点 孩子 抓住他
Get him! Come on, kid! Get him!
哦 不要这样
Oh, man!
伙计们 干得不错
Guys, good effort.
额 兄弟 你来这
Uh, Swackhamer, you got this.
- 快来呀 兄弟 - 哇 好了
- Come on, Swackhamer. - Whoo! Okay.
- 你抓住它了 兄弟 - 你抓住了
- You got it, man. - You got it!
扔出去
Back off! Throw it!
前进 前进 大个子
Tap in. Tap in, big man.
去抓住它 阿克拉克 都是你的了
Go get it, Aklark! It's all yours!
别怕
Don't be afraid.
它能嗅到你的恐惧
It can smell your fear!
- 用它做寿司 - 快点
- Make him sushi! - Come on!
耶
Yeah!
真外行
Amateurs!
哇 我不用看
Wow! I did not need to see that!
对格拉波虫有利的对甘曼也一样有益
What's good for the Graboid is good for the Gummer.
是的
All right.
真恶心
That can't be comfortable.
你用一个大屁针在我的喉咙里捅了一下
You went poking around in my throat with a big-ass needle,
我会生气的
I'd be pissed!
有点尴尬
That is so awkward.
太恶心了
Oh, it smells so bad.
他们应该叫它深喉
They should call him Deep Throat.
太臭了
That is all kinds of nasty.
至少没有在前列腺
At least the gland wasn't in the prostate!
是啊
Yeah.
抱歉 特拉维斯
I'm sorry, Travis.
就这个吗
That's it?
你还可以做点别的
There has to be something more you can do.
还不能治疗
That is no way to treat an HK91!
对不起 伯特
Sorry, Burt.
没事了
It won't happen again.
你应该去冲个澡
With all due respect, soldier, you need a shower.
真是小题大做
What's the damn fuss?
没死 感觉怎样 你不会死的
How do you not die? You never die.
- 甘曼先生 - 长官
- Mr. Gummer. - Sir.
很高兴你来了
Glad to see you up and at them.
现在 很高兴告诉你
Now, it gives me great pleasure to present you
你的联邦税收留置权永久释放
with your permanent federal tax lien release, in perpetuity,
还有所有契据
as well as the title deeds to your property.
签字 盖章
Signed, sealed...
还要交付
And delivered.
- 你可真是太好了 - 是的
- You're too kind. - You're right.
这一物种会是一个特别的生化武器
This species will make an exceptional bio-weapon.
提到格拉波虫 我很少出错 卡茨先生
When it comes to Graboids, I'm rarely wrong, Mr. Cutts.
它带有神经植入物
Mmm-hmm. With the right neuro-implant,
它可能是上帝和国家的掩体
it could be a bunker-buster for God and country.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我一直都和你意见一致
I was right about you all along.
你和你的国防部奴才们 都是一群恶毒的傻瓜
You and your DARPA minions, you're a bunch of malevolent ineptoids!
甘曼先生 你在说什么
What the hell was that, Mr. Gummer?
长官 那就是引爆器
That, sir, is the trigger.
而我就是那个手指
And I am the finger.
听着 我不知道你在干什么
Look, I don't know what you're doing,
但我强烈建议你不要那样做
but I'd strongly advise you not to do it!
那个格拉波虫是美国政府的财产
That Graboid is US government property!
成为一个疯子 真是讨厌
Hate to be a buzzkill.
向它射击 轰下来
Shoot it. Blow it out of the sky!
耶
Yes!
格拉波虫 不怎么样 卡茨先生
Graboids don't make good pets, Mr. Cutts.
祈祷吧 伯特
Preach on it, Burt!
甘曼先生 我的飞机已经准备好 可以出发了
Mr. Gummer, my plane's all packed and ready to go.
- 收到 - 顺便说一句
- Roger that. - By the way,
干得不错
nice work.
老爹说的没错 你真强硬
Dad was right. You are a hard-ass!
告诉你老爹 向他问好
Tell your dad I said, "Hey."
告诉他不用来看我
Tell him not to drop in.
他可不是那种喜欢到处逛的人
He's not really the dropping-in kind of guy.
他是那种喜欢不请自来的
He's more of the barging-in type.
这真是一个地狱般的故事
This is gonna be one hell of a story to tell back home.
告诉他 你比他强
Tell him I said you're a better shot than he ever was.
谢谢 甘曼先生
Thanks, Mr. Gummer.
叫我伯特
Call me Burt!
你知道我不会永远呆在北极圈吧
You know I won't be in the Arctic Circle forever, right?
六个月后 我就回国了
Six months, I'll be back in the States.
你这是在讨好我么
You trying to get sweet with me?
当然
Definitely.
不可能
Never gonna happen.
也许吧
I think it might.
谢谢
Thanks.
为这一切
For everything.
特拉维斯 你从我这学到了啥
Travis, what have you learned from me?
不要相信任何人和事
Uh, to not trust anyone or anything ever?
这是吻别
You call that a goodbye kiss?
一个男人带来了一个大洞
A man brings a big bore .44 Magnum to a fight, not some broke dick .22.
那可是甜蜜的大屌
Broke dick? That was sweet dick.
- 是么 - 是啊
- Oh, was it? - Yeah.
因为极度缺乏任何速度或力量
'Cause that sorely lacked any kind of velocity or stopping power,
更不用说最大的穿透力了
not to mention maximum penetration.
现在谈弹药有点晚
Okay, it's a little late to have
伯特 对吧
the guns-and-ammo talk, Burt. All right?
真可悲
Pathetic.
- 好些了 - 是么
- It was better. - Better?
那是马格努姆44 也许吧
It was no .44 Magnum. .357, maybe.
兄弟 你对亲吻了解多少呢
Dude, what do you know about kissing?
我知道 除非我准备好使用武器 否则我不能把枪拔出来
I know enough not to unholster my weapon unless I'm prepared to use it.
伯特 看到你恢复过来 真好
It's nice to see you back to your old self, Burt.
你说我们回家去晒晒太阳怎么样
What do you say we get on home and get ourselves some real sunshine, huh?
那真是再好不过了
Sounds like perfection, Pops.
老爹
Pops.